Finding Aid for the Kenneth Peach Papers PASC.0256
UCLA Library Special Collections
Kenneth Peach papers
1951-1982
UCLA Library Special Collections
Peach, Kenneth
PASC.0256
1.25 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
Kenneth Peach, Sr. was a special effects artists and set photographer. The collection consists primarily of television scripts related to the Peach's career.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift, 2003.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9948572263606533
Biography/History
Kenneth D. Peach (Ken) was born in EL Reno, OK on March 6, 1903. He began his career in motion pictures at about the age of 20 and became a director of photography in 1926. He worked with composite processes, miniatures, montages and matte shots for Tiffany Pictures for two years, then joined Fred Jackman's technical effects department at Warner Brothers- First National for almost three years. He was a process cinematographer for various independent companies for two years and was with Columbia for a year. In 1931 he joined the RKO Radio camera effects department, where he worked on such notable films as The Most Dangerous Game and King Kong. In 1933 Peach began what would become a long association with Hal Roach Studio, where he was director of photography of many of the Laurel and Hardy comedies, including Sons of the Desert and Dirty Work. After serving in the US Navy, he did the special effects and process photography on several independent pictures eventually going to RKO until 1950. Around this time, he became director of photography for the Cisco Kid features and 26 episodes of the Cisco Kid television series, among other projects. During the 1950s we was associated with numerous television series including Boston Blackie, Texaco Star Theatre, and Lassie among others. He also photographed several television features. Into the 1960s Peach continued to work on both theatrical features and television projects until his retirement in 1984. Peach died February 27, 1988 after a long illness.
Scope and Content
The collection primarily of television scripts related to the career of special effects artists and set photographer, Kenneth Peach, Sr. Also included in the collection is a small number of crew sheets and group photographs. Notably absent from the collection is material related to the number of motion picture projects in which he was involved.
Organization and Arrangement
The collection is arranged by project titles.
Television scripts.; Cinematographers -- Archives.; Peach, Kenneth -- Archives
- ABC Wide World of Mystery, 1975 Sept 30 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  General note
  Murder On The Mind - Teleplay by Howard Rayfiel
- Adventures of The Falcon, 1954 May 6 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Big Heist (The) - revised script and crew sheet
- Best of The West, 1980 Mar 19 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  By Earl Pomerantz - script and crew sheet
- Big Time, The, 1958 Feb 2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Episode in Macao - Revised script - by Frank Gill, Jr. and G. Carleton Brown
- Boston Blackie, 1951 Sept 29 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Delmark Diamond Case (The) by Mike Raison - final master script
- Bumpers, 1977 Mar 04 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Script and crew sheet
- Checkmate, 1961 Feb 24 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Goodbye, Griff by Steven Thornley - script
- Cheers, 1982 Apr 12 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Give Me A Ring Sometime by Glen and Les Charles - script and crew sheet
- City Beneath The Sea, 1970 Aug (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Photo and crew sheet
- Cowboy 'G' Men, no date (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Stolen Dynamite by Buckley Angell - TV screenplay with crew sheet and photograph
- Crew Sheets (Loose), no date (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Crew sheets from miscellaneous projects
- Dollars and Sense, 1960 Feb 20 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Story of Personal Money Management (The) - for The American Bankers Association
- Dr. Hudson's Secret Journal, no date (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Actress Story (The) - script and crew sheet
- Dr. Hudson's Secret Journal, no date (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Ann Talbot Story (The) - Screenplay by Robert Bassing
- Dundee And The Culhane, 1966 Sept 16 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Cat-In-The-Bag-Brief (The) by Sam Rolfe - script and crew sheet
- Family Theater's Thanksgiving Hour, no date (Box 3, Folder 5)
  That I May See - script
- Follow The Sun, 1961 Oct (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Fury, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Gangbusters, no date (Box 1, Folder 3)
  John Richard Bayless - Prod. #216 script
- Goodbye Girl, The, 1980 Apr 07 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  By Allan Katz - script and crew sheet
- H.R. Pufnstuf, 1969 May 05 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Magic Road (The) by Lennie Weinrib, Paul Harrison and Bob Ridolphi - script and crew sheet
- Harry's Back in Town, 1978 Nov 15 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  By Steve Gordon - script
- Here Comes Donald, no date (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Donald Takes A Vacation by Sidney Miller and Hall Fimberg - script with crew sheet
- Lassie, 1959 Oct (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Lassiter, 1966 Nov 01 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Tonight We Make Them Cry by Richard Alan Simmons - script and crew sheet
- Long, Hot Summer, The, 1965 Sept 15 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Desperate Innocent - Formerly named At Twilight Came A Bird's Song by Oliver Crawford - first draft script
- Maureen Stapleton Pilot, The, no date (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Annette's Arrival - script
- Michael Shayne, 1960 July 22 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Die Like a Dog by Robert Bloomfield - revised script and crew sheet
- Millionaire, 1957 June 26 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Barbara Lydon - script
- Mr. And Mrs. North TV, 1954 Feb 22 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  A Placid Affair - script
- New Adventures of Charlie Chan, 1956 Dec 19 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Your Money Or Your Wife - Teleplay by Richard Grey and - final draft script with crew sheet
- New Adventures of Huck Finn, The, 1967 Sept 07 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Last Labor of Hercules (The) by David Duncan script and crew sheet
- Night After Night, 1978 May 24 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  By David Lloyd and Marshall Brickman - script and crew sheet
- Odd Couple, The, 1974 Oct 23 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Two Men On A Hoarse by Martin Donovan - script
- Phyllis, 1975 Oct 31 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  So Lonely I Could Cry by Mary Kay Place and Valerie Curtin - script and crew sheet
- Rhoda, 1976 Dec 23 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Second Time Around (The) - by Pat Nardo and Gloria Banta - script and crew sheet
- Silver Springs, 1966 Aug (Box 1, Folder 19)
  By Claire Kennedy - script
- Taxi, 1982 Sept 22 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Crime And Punishment by Katherine Green scipt and crew sheet
- There's Always Room, 1976 Sept 13 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  By Michael Leeson - 2nd revised final draft script
- There's Always Room, 1976 Aug 30 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  By Michael Leeson - script
- Thunderhead, 1962 Dec 10 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Day Of The Eagle - script and crew sheet
- Two of Us, The, 1980 Feb 27 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  By Charlie Hauck - script
- Unexpected, The, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With Malice Toward One by Lawrence and Lee - script
- Unidentified project, no date (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Group photographs of project crews.
- You're Only Young Twice, 1964 Dec 02 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  By Stan Dreben and Lorenzo Semple, Jr - script and crew sheet.
  Episode of Vacation Playhouse.